Catherine Viviano Gallery Records
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1939-1985, Series 2:; (Boxes 3-6; 5.5 linear feet)
  - General Correspondence, 1939-1985, 2.1:
    - Varcasia, Francesco - Versic, Dori, 1950-1974, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
      Varcasia, Francesco
      Varkell, Paul
      Venturi, Lionello
      Verrell, Hal
      Versic, Dori
    - Vespignani, Renzo - Visser 'T Hooft, Martha, 1950-1964, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
      Vespignani, Renzo
      Vilaro, Jorge Pace
      Visser 'T Hooft, Martha
    - Viviano, Catherine, 1949-1972, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 24-25)
    - Volpi, P. - Vursell, Harold, 1950-1977, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
      Volpi, P. (La Cucina Italiana)
      Von Bolschwing, Gisbert
      Von Schnnitzler, Lilly
      Vursell, Harold
    - Wade, Jane - Wakita, Kazu, 1960-1978, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
      Wade, Jane
      Waddell, Chauncey
      Waith, Eugene M.
      Wakita, Kazu
    - Walden School - Walter, Paul F., 1954-1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
      Walden School (Parents Association, Art Committee)
      Waldmann, John R.
      Wallace, Mrs. William
      Walsh, Annie
      Walter, Paul F.
    - Warner, Edna (Mrs. Keith Warner), 1960, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Warner, Keith, 1951-1959, undated (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
    - Warren, Agatha (Mrs. Leonard Warren) - Washburn, Rodney, 1955-1971 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      Warren, Agatha (Mrs. Leonard Warren)
      Warren, Whitney
      Washburn, Deric
      Washburn, Gordon and Ruth
      Washburn, Rodney
    - Watherston, Margaret - Weidler, Charlotte, 1960-1976, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
      Watherston, Margaret
      Watkins, James Sherman
      Wegweiser, Roslyn (The H. H. Wilson Company)
      Wehr, Edward R.
      Weidler, Charlotte
    - Weil, Florence and Richard - Weiner, Ted, 1955-1964, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
      Weil, Florence and Richard
      Weiner, Ted
    - Weingarten, Alan H. - Weir, Maurice, 1959-1972, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
      Weinstein, Alan H. (University of Saskatchewan)
      Weinstein, Mary (Mrs. Harold X. Weinstein)
      Weinstock, Joel W. (Prints International)
      Weir, Maurice (Maurice Weir Associates)
    - Weisner, Ulrich - Welton Beckert and Associates, 1959-1977, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
      Weisner, Ulrich (Kunsthalle Bielefeld)
      Weiss, Mrs. Frederick T.
      Weiss, Mrs. Richard A.
      Welton Becket and Associates
    - Werblow, Charles S. - Westcott, Glenway, 1960-1974, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
      Werblow, Charles S.
      Werner, Joseph
      Westcott, Barbara (Mrs. L. B. Westcott)
      Westcott, Glenway
    - Wharton, Carly - Whitlock, Helen, 1957-1967, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
      Wharton, Carly
      Whitcomb, David
      White, David O.
      White, Vera
      Whitlet, G. S. (Studio International Art Monthly)
      Whitlock, Helen
    - Whyte, Bertha (Mrs. Malcolm Whyte) - Whyte, John, 1955-1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
      Whyte, Bertha (Mrs. Malcom Whyte)
      Whyte, John
    - Widdis, Frank - Williams, Wayne Francis, 1953-1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
      Widdis, Frank
      Wilcox, Mrs. E. T. (Harvard University Press)
      Wilder, Mitchell (Director of Presentation, Colonial Williamsburg)
      Wilke, Ulfert
      Williams, Bob
      Williams, E. E.
      Williams, Wayne Francis
    - Willis, Jack - Wing, Elaine, 1957-1969 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      Willis, Jack
      Wilson, Alfred and Josefa
      Wing, Elaine
    - Winn, William A. - Wohlinger, George, 1951-1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
      Winn, William A.
      Winter, Anne
      Wise, Howard E.
      Wisner, John B.
      Wohlinger, George
    - Wolf, Mr. - Wolsky, Milton, 1954-1969 (Box 6, Folder 43)
      Wolf, Mr.
      Wolfe, Constance
      Wolfe, Townsend (Wooster-Community Art Center)
      Wolsky, Milton
    - Wolosoff, Gloria - Wurdig, Chlodig, 1952-1976, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
      Wolosoff, Gloria
      Wood, Clement
      Woods, Thomas
      Worcester, Charles H.
      Wright, Norman B.
      Wurdig, Chlodig
    - Wurtzberger, Alan - Yingling, O. C., 1956-1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
      Wurtzberger, Alan
      Yamamoto, Noriko
      Yamashita, Noboru
      Yingling, O. C.
    - Yunkers, Mr. and Mrs. Adja (Dore Ashton), 1955-1965, undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Zajac, Jack - Ziebolz, Herbert 1950-1974, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
      Zajac, Jack
      Zaoussailoff, Choura
      Zariski, Yale Cagli
      Zaug, Shelley (Mrs. Dawson Duncan)
      Zeisler, Richard Spiro
      Ziebolz, Herbert
    - Zimmerman, Frederick and Dorothy, 1962-1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Zinsser, William and Joyce - Zoromskis, Kazimieras, 1953-1965, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
      Zinsser, William and Joyce
      Zivi, Walter
      Zoromskis, Kazimieras
    - Unidentified Correspondents, Surnames Illegible, 1950-1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Unidentified Correspondents, Surnames Omitted, 1951-1973, undated, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 51-52)
    - Loose Envelope and Fragment of Envelope, 1961, undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence with Museums, Galleries, and Art-Related Institutions, United States, 1950-1984, 2.2:
    This subseries consists of the gallery's letters to representatives of museums, dealers, independent schools, universities, colleges, and non-for-profit institutions. Subjects discussed are market valuations and appraisals; acquisitions and sales; and loans of artwork for exhibitions.
    Correspondence also includes memoranda, consignment agreements, loan forms, shipping and receipt of objects forms, lists of artwork with valuations and sale prices, insurance claim forms, ledger pages with sale prices of artwork, guest lists, press releases, printed material, clippings, exhibition announcements, invitations, and photographs of artwork.
    Viviano maintained an ongoing correspondence with numerous public and university museums, galleries, and arts organizations in the United States. Of particular note, the correspondence with the Museum of Modern Art's (New York) Department of Circulating Exhibitions and Junior Council provides a rich source of information on acquisitions and sales from the 1950's through 1960's. Also found is correspondence pertaining to Catherine Viviano's involvement in professional associations.
    Files are arranged alphabetically, by institution, and the materials within the folders are in chronological order.
    - Addison Gallery of American Art, Phillips Academy, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Alan Gallery, 1954-1963 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Albany Institute of Art, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Albright Art Gallery, The Buffalo Arts Academy1952-1961, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 57-59)
    - Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1962-1970, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 60-63)
    - Allan Frumkin Gallery, 1952-1976 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - The Alpha Gallery, 1968-1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1954-1970, undated, (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 66-68)
    - American Center for Students and Artists, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1950-1977, undated, (8 folders) (Box 6, Folder 70-77)
    - American Friends of the Hebrew University, 1957-1964 (Box 6, Folder 78)
    - American Society for Technion, circa 1969 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    - American University, 1956-1957, undated (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Archives of American Art, 1960-1969, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 81-82)
    - Arizona Art Foundation, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Arkansas Arts Center, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Art Dealers Association,1961-1969, undated, (9 folders) (Box 6, Folder 85-93)
    - Art Association of Indianapolis, The John Herron Art Institute, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Art in America ,1960-1961, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Art Institute of Chicago, 1950-1968, undated, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 3-6)
    - Art News, 1950-1968, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Art Theft Archive, 1977, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Arts Club of Chicago, 1951-1961, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
    - Artist-Tenants Association, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Artists Equity Association, 1954-1958 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Arts (formerly The Art Digest), 1951-1964 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Asia Society, 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Baltimore Art Museum, 1950-1968, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
    - The Barnes Foundation, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Berenice Kandeland Associates, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Berkshire Arts Center, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Berkshire Museum, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Betty McLean Gallery, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Bianchini Gallery, 1960, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Birmingham Museum of Art, 1951-1959 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Boston Arts Festival, 1956-1961 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Brandeis University, 1954-1961 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Bristol Art Museum, 1964-1968, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 27-29)
    - Brockton Art Center, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - The Brooklyn Museum, 1951-1968, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 31-32)
    - The Brooklyn Museum Art School, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, 1951-1960 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Brown University, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Bundy Art Gallery,1957-1963, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 36-37)
    - Busch-Reisinger Museum, Harvard University,1957-1968 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Butler Art Institute,circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - California Palace of the Legion of Honor, 1950-1968 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Capricorn Gallery, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Carneal House Gallery, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Carnegie Institute, 1950-1968, undated, (10 folders) (Box 7, Folder 43-52)
    - Carroll Reece Museum, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Charles M. Feingarten Gallery, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Christie's, 1969-1979, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Cincinnati Modern Art Society, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - City Art Museum of St. Louis, 1954-1970, undated, (7 folders) (Box 7, Folder 57-63)
    - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1959-1968, undated, (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 64-68)
    - Colgate University, 1954-1973 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center, 1953-1967, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 70-73)
    - Columbia University, Casa Italiana, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - The Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts, 1955-1961 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Committee of Artists' Societies at The New York World's Fair (1964-1965), 1964 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Contemporary Arts Center, 1955-1961 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Contemporary Arts Museum, 1957-1966, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 78-79)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1956-1963, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 80-83)
    - Cornell University, 1950-1968 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Cranbook Academy of Art, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - Currier Gallery of Art, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - The Cushman Gallery, Inc., 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Dallas Museum for Contemporary Arts, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1953-1968, undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 89-90)
    - Dartmouth College, Hopkins Center, 1962-1968 (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - Davison Art Center, Wesleyan University, 1953-1965 (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - The Dayton Art Institute, 1951-1960 (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - DeCordova and Dana Museum and Park, 1955-1974, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 94-95)
    - Denver Art Museum, 1954-1963, (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 96-99)
    - Des Moines Art Center, 1954-1963, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 100-102)
    - Detroit Institute of Arts, 1950-1960, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 103-105)
    - De Witt and De Hart Residential Interiors, undated (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - Downtown Gallery, 1954-1968 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    - Duke University, 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 108)
    - East Cleveland Museum Galleries, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 109)
    - Egone Gallery, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - Elvehjem Art Center, University of Wisconsin, 1969-1974 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Enoch Pratt Free Library, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Esther Robles Gallery, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 113)
    - Fairweather Hardin Gallery, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 114)
    - Finch College Museum, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 115)
    - Florida Gulf Coast Art Center, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 116)
    - Fogg Art Museum, Harvard University, 1957-1973, undated, (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 117-119)
    - Frank Perls Galleries, 1953-1968 (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - Frick Art Reference Library, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 121)
    - Fulton Gallery, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 122)
    - The Gallery of Modern Art, the Huntingdon Hartford Collection, 1965-1967, undated (Box 7, Folder 123)
    - Grand Rapids Art Museum, 1952-1973 (Box 7, Folder 124)
    - Grinnell College, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 125)
    - The Guild Hall, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - Harriet Griffin Gallery, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - The High Museum of Art, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 129)
    - The Hyde Collection, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Illinois Wesleyan University, School of Art, 1954-1963 (Box 7, Folder 131)
    - Indiana University, Department of Arts and Sciences, Fine Arts Department, 1950-1968 (Box 7, Folder 132)
    - Institute of Contemporary Art, 1958-1962, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 133-134)
    - The International Culture Center for Youth in Jerusalem, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Iowa State Teachers College, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - The Isaac Delgado Museum of Art, 1959-1968 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Istituto Italiano di Cultura, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Italian Embassy, Cultural Division, 1956-1963, undated (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - Italian Historical Society of America, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - The J. B. Speed Art Gallery, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - James Gallery, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - James David Gallery, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Jefferson Place Gallery, 1959-1961, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Jewish Museum (New York), 1958, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Joseph Devernay Contemporary Art, 1972-1984, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Joslyn Art Museum, 1955-1963 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - The Junior Art Gallery, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Kansas City Public Library, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Kansas State College, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Katonah Gallery, 1960-1964 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Kent State University, Van Deusen Art Gallery, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Kimball Art Foundation, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - La Boetie (New York), 1972-1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - La Napoule Art Foundation, Henry Clewes Foundation, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Landau Gallery, 1953-1967 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Larcada Gallery, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Laurent Galleries, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Layton Art Institute, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Lee Gallery, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - The Library of Congress, 1973, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Long Island Arts Center, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Los Angeles County Art Museum, 1951-1968, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
    - M. H. De Young Memorial Museum, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - M. Knoedler and Co., Inc., 1955-1969, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - MacDowell Colony, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Marion Koogler McNay Art Institute, 1962-1965, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Marlborough Gallery, Inc., 1974 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1953-1959, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Martin Schweig Gallery, 1955-1959 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - The Maryland Institute College of Art, 1976-1977, undated (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1955-1964, undated, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 34-36)
    - Mattatuck Museum, 1963-1967 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Maxwell Davidson Gallery, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Metro International Magazine of Contemporary Art, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1950-1968, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 40-41)
    - Miami Museum of Modern Art, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Michigan State University, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Mills College, 1957-1963 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Milwaukee Art Center, 1964-1969 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Milwaukee Art Institute, 1952-1956 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - The Minneapolis Institute of Art, 1951-1955, undated, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 47-50)
    - The Mint Museum, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Mississippi State College for Women, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Mount Holyoke College, 1951-1961 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Mount Vernon Art Association, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1954-1958 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1955-1960, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 56-57)
    - Museum of Fine Arts of Houston, 1954-1974, undated, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 58-61)
    - The Museum of Modern Art (New York), 1949-1970, undated, (16 folders) (Box 8, Folder 62-77)
    - The Museum of Primitive Art, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Myrtle Todes Art Gallery, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Nardin Galleries, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - National Gallery of Art, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - The National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Nebraska Art Association, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - The Newark Museum, 1956-1978 (Box 8, Folder 84)
    - New Canaan Library, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - New Haven Festival of Arts, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - New Jersey State Museum, 1971-1978 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - New York University, circa 1960s (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - The North Carolina Museum of Art, 1957-1966, undated (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - North Shore Community Art Center, 1959-1969 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Oakland Art Museum, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Oberlin College, The Dudley Peter Allen Memorial Art Museum, 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Ohio University, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - The Ohio State University, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - Pan American Union, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc., 1960 (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Pasadena Art Museum, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Paul Kantor Gallery, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - The Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1950-1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 99-100)
    - Philadelphia Art Alliance, 1959-1966, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 101-102)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, Art Sales and Rental Gallery, 1967, undated (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Phoenix Art Museum, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Portland Art Museum, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Prakapas Gallery, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Princeton University, the Art Museum, 1969-1974, undated (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - Providence Art Club, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - Randolph Macon Woman's College, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - The Renaissance Society, University of Chicago, 1950-1955 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, 1955-1959 (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - Richard Feigen Gallery, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - Rutgers University, University Art Gallery, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Sanford Hanauer Associates, 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1953-1968, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 115-116)
    - Sara Barnes Roby Foundation, 1962-1966 (Box 8, Folder 117)
    - Sara Lawrence College, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 118)
    - Scott Elliott Gallery, 1974, undated (Box 8, Folder 119)
    - The Sculptor's Guild, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 120)
    - Seattle Art Museum, 1965-1969 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Smith College, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 122)
    - Smithsonian Institution, Traveling Exhibition Service, 1951-1966, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 123-124)
    - The Society of the Four Arts, 1951-1954 (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - The Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1954-1978, undated, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 126-129)
    - Southern Vermont Art Center, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 130)
    - The Spanish International Pavilion Foundation, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - Spencer A. Samuels and Company, Ltd., 1967 (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - Springfield Museum of Fine Arts, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 133)
    - St. Louis Art Museum, 1978, undated (Box 8, Folder 134)
    - St. Paul Art Center, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 135)
    - State University of New York, State Teachers College, 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - Staten Island Institute of Arts and Sciences, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 137)
    - Syracuse University, College of Fine Arts, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - Three Two Seven Gallery, Inc., 1961 (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - Tibor de Nagy Gallery, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 140)
    - The Toledo Museum of Art, 1951-1968, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 141-142)
    - University of Bridgeport, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - University of California at Berkeley, 1959-1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - University of Colorado at Boulder, 1956-1968, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - University of Georgia, 1966-1967, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - University of Illinois, Department of Art, College of Fine and Applied Arts, 1950-1964, undated, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 5-8)
    - University of Iowa, 1954, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - University of Miami, Lowe Galleries, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - University of Michigan, 1954-1963, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
    - University of Minnesota, The University Gallery, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - University of Nebraska Art Galleries, 1951-1963, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 14-16)
    - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Ackland Art Center, 1964-1976 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - University of Notre Dame, 1958-1974, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 18-19)
    - University of South Florida, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - University of Virginia, Mary Washington College, 1956-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 21-22)
    - Valley House, 1956-1959 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Art, 1950-1959, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1954-1976, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 25-28)
    - Walker Art Center, 1953-1964, undated, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 29-32)
    - Washburn Gallery, 1964-1978, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Washington Square Galleries, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Washington University, Department of Art and Archaeology, 1952-1963, undated, (6 folders) (Box 9, Folder 35-40)
    - Weatherspoon Art Gallery, University of North Carolina, 1974, undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Wellesley College, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1950-1965, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 43-45)
    - Wildenstein and Co., Inc., 1956, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, Atkins Museum of the Fine Arts, 1953-1968, undated, (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 47-51)
    - Williams College Museum of Art, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Wisconsin University, Department of Art Education, 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Worcester Art Museum, 1952-1970 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - World House Gallery, 1956-1962 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Yale University Art Gallery, 1953-1968, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 56-59)
    - Yale University Christian Association, 1960, undated (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence with Museums, Galleries, and Art-Related Institutions Abroad, 1951-1975, 2.3: